Guide to the Ester Hernandez Papers
Department of Special Collections
The Ester M. Hernandez papers
1957-2001
M1301
Hernandez, Ester
53.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
The collection contains original artwork, photographic images, periodical articles regarding both Hernandez and many of her contemporaries, original manuscripts, audio and visual recordings documenting interviews and political events, and ephemera gathered from artists, performers, and political/social activists and events.
Access
Collection is open for research, except for Subseries 6.6 Artist's Files: Alice Walker; materials must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of intended use.
Acquisition Information
In part purchased and in part a gift of Ester M. Hernandez, 2001.
Biography / Administrative History
Hernandez is an artist of the first generation of Chicano and Chicana artists who participated in the Chicano art movement that began in the late 1960s as part of the Chicano civil rights movement. Her collection represents more than twenty-five years of involvement in many of the most important historical activities of this period, including the farmworkers' movement, the feminist movement, international environmental movements, and the art movement itself, including the visual, literary, and performing arts. A California Bay Area artist, Hernandez is primarily known as a printmaker and pastel artist. She has also created a lesser-known body of photographic and performance work.
Scope and Content of Collection
Includes correspondence, contracts, exhibition brochures and catalogues, newspaper and journal articles and reviews, books, original manuscript stories, interviews (both of the artist and of other artists, writers, and performers conducted by Hernandez), slides, photogrpahs and negatives, works of art (prints, posters, drawings, pastels) by the artist and other artists, videos, audio tapes, cd's and albums, and costumes and accessories.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Chavez, Cesar 1927-; Hadad, Astrid; Huerta, Dolores 1930-; Mendoza, Lydia; Walker, Alice 1944-; United Farm Workers of America.; Mexican American Art.
Container List
- Artwork, Series 1; 17 linear ft.
  Series I contains many examples of Hernandez's work on several types of media, including Original Work on Paper, Sketches, Prints, linoleum Etching Blocks, and sets of Transparencies used in the printing process. Also in the series can be found Work by Others acquired by Hernandez.
  - Original Work On Paper, Subseries 1.1
    - Black Slippers, 1974; pastel, 44cm x 28cm, mounted on posterboard, 62cm x 46cm (Box 1)
    - Frida's Death Mask, 1979; pastel, 46cm x 61cm (Box 1)
    - Abuelita, a study, 1980; pastel, 61cm x 46cm (Box 1)
    - Irene, 1976; pastel, 46cm x 61cm (Box 1)
    - The Beating of Dolores Huerta by the San Francisco Police, 1988; charcoal on pastel paper, 71cm x 55cm (Box 2)
    - The Ferris Wheel Ride, 1991; charcoal on pastel paper, 71cm x 55cm (Box 2)
    - Juntos al Futuro, 1991; pastel, 76cm x 51cm (Box 2)
    - Dia De Los Muertos - Janitzio, Michoacan, a study, 1990; conte crayon on paper, 57.5cm x 77cm (Box 2)
    - Portrait of Renee - Russian River Water Colors, 1 of 3, 1988; graphite and watercolor study, 26cm x 18cm (Box 3)
    - Portrait Seated - Russian River Water Colors, 2 of 3, 1988; graphite and watercolor study, 26cm x 18cm (Box 3)
    - The Crow - Russian River Water Colors, 3 of 3, 1988; graphite and watercolor study, 26cm x 18cm (Box 3)
    - Self-portrait - Berkeley, 1977; ink on Japanese paper, 31cm x 23.5cm (Box 3)
    - Dona Maria Buen Rostro - Oakland, CA, 1986; graphite on paper, 45cm x 38 (Box 3)
    - La Ofrenda I, 1988; pencil sketch including notes on color separation, 36cm x 28cm (Box 3)
    - La Ofrenda I, 1988; original water color study for screen print, 38cm x 28.5cm (Box 3)
    - La Ofrenda I, 1988; water color study, 43cm x 28cm (Box 3)
    - California Special, 1988; original water color study, 66cm x 51cm (Box 3)
    - Dona Maria - La Curandera, 1985; conte crayon on paper, 63cm x 48cm (Box 4)
    - Dona Maria Buen Rostro, 1985; graphite on paper, 63cm x 48cm (Box 4)
    - Greetings From Sunny California II, 1994; mono-screenprint, 66cm x 50.5cm (Box 4)
    - Gracias a la Vida, 1992; water color on paper, 33cm x 76cm (Box 5)
      Mural proposal for Centro Latino de San Francisco, color layout and design
    - La Virgen de Guadalupe Recibiendo a Cesar Chavez, 1994; china marker study, 58.5cm x 76cm (Box 5)
    - The Mastectomy I, 1993; acrylic on paper, 76cm x 55cm (Box 5)
    - The Mastectomy II, 1993; acrylic on paper, 76cm x 55cm (Box 5)
    - La Virgen de Guadalupe Recibiendo a Cesar Chavez - a study, 1995; graphite on black German etching paper 75.5cm x 99cm (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous Sketches, 1.2
    - [11 Sketches by Ester Hernandez], Pen and ink [felt tip marker?] on poster, 28cm x 35.5cm (Box 6)
      Series of sketches depicting: artists/artisans at work; peasants performing tasks; a mask; and Mexican cultural iconographic representations.
    - Miscellaneous Sketches by Ester Hernandez (Box 6)
    - Woman, Mother, Student, 1975 (Box 6)
  - Prints, 1.3
    - Viva la Musica, 1981; lithograph on rag, 33cm x 24cm (Box 7)
    - HIgh Rolliando, 1981; monoprint, 33cm x 24cm (Box 7)
    - Medito, 1976; etching, artist's proof, 32cm x 24cm (Box 7)
    - la Virgen de Guadalupe Defendiendo Los Derechos de Los Xicanos, 1976; block print, 32cm x 24cm (Box 7)
    - Lydia Mendoza, 1986; mixed media print; transfer, embossment, monoprint, 28.5cm x 38cm (Box 7)
    - The Nightmare, 1988; monoprint, 38cm x 48cm (Box 7)
    - El Diablo, 1985; monoprint, 38cm x 48cm (Box 7)
    - Amiga, 1985; aquatint etching, 30.5cm x 40cm (Box 7)
    - Soldier Boys, ca. 1980; color xerox collage, 1 of 5, 43cm x 28cm (Box 7)
    - Amor Bonito[?], ca. 1980; color xerox collage, 2 of 5, 43cm x 28cm (Box 7)
    - Sisters - The Grapefields ca. 1938[?], ca. 1980; color xerox collage, 3 of 5, 43cm x 28cm (Box 7)
    - Musical Dreams[?], ca. 1980; color xerox collage, 4 of 5, 43cm x 28cm (Box 7)
    - Sisters - The Cottonfields ca. 1938, ca. 1980; color xerox collage, 5 of 5, 43cm x 28cm (Box 7)
    - Paul Revere On His Mustang, 1976; print[?], artist's proof, 29.5cm x 45cm (Box 7)
    - Yo y Pride, 1985; print[?], 2/5, 38cm x 56.5cm (Box 8)
    - Dia de los Muertos Xicanas, 1983; etching, artist's print, 37.5cm x 56.5 (Box 8)
    - Never On Sunday, 1980; aquatint, 1/3, 42.5cm x 55cm (Box 8)
    - Eagle Print I, 1985; mixed media, 75.5cm x 56.5cm (Box 8)
    - Frida y Yo, 1998; lithograph, 70/100, 56.5cm x 76cm (Box 8)
    - Corazon II, 1986; collograph embossment, 55cm x 76cm (Box 9)
    - Dance of the Eagle Spirit, 1985; mixed media, artist's proof, 72.5cm x 53.5cm (Box 9)
    - Border Bruja, 1994; ghost monoprint, 2/2, 66cm x 51cm (Box 9)
    - Madonna Moderna, 1994; mono screenprint, 51cm x 66cm (Box 9)
    - La Piscadora, 1989; mono screenprint with pastels and medium, 76cm x 56cm (Box 9)
    - Sun Mad, 1982; print 10/100, 56cm x 43cm (Box 10)
    - Xicana-India, 1973; print, 57cm x 45cm (Box 10)
      First screen-print by Ester Hernandez
    - Tejido de los Desaparecidos (Weaving of the Disappeared), 1984; print 20/41, second printing, 45.5cm x 60cm (Box 10)
    - Tejido de los Desaparecidos (Weaving of the Disappeared), 1984; print 84/100, first printing, 43cm x 56cm (Box 10)
    - Liberdad, 1976; print 13/50, 43cm x 56cm (Box 10)
      Original print was an etching
    - La Llorna, 1982; print 77/100, 56cm x 43cm (Box 10)
    - From the Arawak Indians to Norma Jean Croy, 1992; print, 66cm x 50.5cm (Box 11)
      Work signed by Ester Hernandez and Norma Jean Croy
    - Homenaje a Cesar Chavez, 1993; print #74/101, 56cm x 76cm (Box 11)
    - California Special, 1988; print #4/74, 66cm x 51cm (Box 11)
    - El Tacon de Astrid, 1995; print #34/61, 56cm x 76cm (Box 11)
    - Heroes and Saints, 1992; print, 59cm x 76.5cm (Box 12)
      Worked signed by Ester Hernandez and Cherrie Moraga
    - Luna Llena / Full Moon, 1990; print #33/100, 76.5cm x 56cm (Box 12)
    - Mis Madres, 1990; print #12/86, 76.5cm x 59cm (Box 12)
    - Lydia Mendoza Ciudad Juarez, Mexico, 1937, 1987; print #4/89, 58.5cm x 76.5cm (Box 12)
    - La Ofrenda II, 1990; print #4/84, 76.5cm x 56cm (Box 12)
    - La Ofrenda, 1988; print #1/62, 95cm x 63.5cm (Box 13)
    - Cosmic Cruise, 1990; print #1/6, artist's proof, 96cm x 65.5cm (Box 13)
    - If This Is Death, I Like It, 1991; print #69/70, artist's proof, 88cm x 71cm (Box 13)
    - Indito, print #6/25, 40.5cm x 33cm (Box 14)
    - Contra Vida, n.d.; monoprint, chine colle, 76cm x 57cm (Box 14)
    - La Xicana '89, 1989; 56.5cm x 76cm (Box 14)
    - Her Cry Was Heard Throughout the World (Mother Afrika), 1986; monoprint, chine colle, 75cm x 57cm (Box 14)
    - Encuentros, 1996[?]; offset lithograph color proofs, 76cm x 55.5cm (Box 14)
      6 individual prints of increasing color intensity; 1 print listed as missing by appraiser.
    - Indigena, 1996; offset lithograph, #75/80 76cm x 55cm (Box 15)
    - American Bisontennial, 1976; aquatint embossment, artist's proofs, 68cm x 58cm (Box 15)
      4 versions, varying color tints, orientations
    - Border Flower, 1994; pastel screenprint, 50.5cm x 66cm (Box 15)
    - State of California, 1994; monoscreenprint, 50.5cm x 66cm (Box 15)
  - Etching Blocks, 1.4
    - La Virgen de Guadalupe Defendiendo los Derechos de los Xicanas, Etching plate covered with asphaltum (Box 16)
    - Liberdad, Etching plate covered with asphaltum (Box 16)
    - Liberdad, Linoleum etching block (Box 16)
  - Transparencies, 1.5
    - Tejido de los Desaparecidos (Weaving of the Disappeared), 1984; posterboard, 76cm x 81cm; transparency, 80cm x 81cm (Box 17)
      Printed images pasted to posterboard, single transparency overlay (negative)
    - If This Is Death, I Like It, 1984; sketch paper, 101.5cm x 71cm; transparencies, 114.5cm x 71cm (Box 18)
      Original sketch on paper, with a series of 12 transparencies making up the final screenprint.
    - Indigena, 1996; transparencies, 63cm x 91cm (Box 19)
      A series of 3 transparencies.
    - Study - "La Virgen de Guadalupe Recibiando a Cesar Chavez", January, 1995; color sketch on paper, 59cm x 74cm; transparency, 58.5cm x 75cm (Box 19)
    - Poster - Viva Cesar Chavez, Commemorative Celebration, Stanford University, 4/12/1997; graph paper layout, 57cm x 37.5cm; transparencies, 58.5cm x 75cm (Box 20)
    - Poster - From the Arawak Indians to Norma Jean Croy: Benefit Announcement, 9/19/1992; transparencies, 67.5cm x 45.5cm (Box 20)
      Series of 6 transparencies.
    - Mis Madres, 1990; transparencies, 69cm x 54cm (Box 20)
      Series of 2 transparencies.
    - California Special, 1988; transparencies, 65.5cm x 50cm (Box 21)
    - La Ofrenda II, 1990; vellum sketch, 75.5cm x 55.5cm transparencies, 79cm x 57cm (Box 22)
      Set of 8 transparencies, 1 vellum sketch
    - La Ofrenda I, pencil on posterboard, 86cm x 60cm (Box 22)
    - Homenaje a Cesar Chavez, 1993; transparencies, 57cm x 80cm (Box 23)
      Set of 4 transparencies
    - Luna Llena / Full Moon, 1990; sketch on vellum, 76cm x 58cm; transparencies, 77cm x 53 cm (Box 23)
      Set of 5 sketches and transparencies
    - Encuentros, 1996[?]; transparencies, 95cm x 62.5cm (Box 24)
      Set of 5 transparencies
    - El Tacon de Astrid, 1995; transparencies, 63.5cm x 80cm (Box 24)
      Set of 9 transparencies
    - The Cosmic Cruise, 1989; small transparencies, 43cm x 56cm; large transparencies, 96cm x 64cm;sketch, 58.5cm x 76cm (Box 25)
      Set of 15 transparencies and sketches
    - Galeria de la Raza Exhibition Poster: Sun Mad Raisin featured image, 1995[?]; clear plastic covered poster, 172.5cm x 120.5cm (Box 26)
      25th Anniversary Show, Yerba Buena Gardens, San Francisco: Sept. 12 through Dec. 10, 1995[?]
  - Prints and Work by Others, 1.6
    - Return of the Short-handled Hoe: Emmanuel Montoya, October, 1981; #7/10, 38cm x 28.5cm (Box 27)
    - Este no lo es menos: Enrique Uragoya[sp?], 1988; #9/40, 37cm x 31.5cm (Box 27)
      Inscribed: "Para Ester"
    - Don Juan's Retreat: Ralph Maradiaga, 1973; Artist's proof #1, 28cm x 35cm (Box 27)
    - Hombre de la Montanas: Ralph Maradiaga, 1973[?]; Artist's proof #2, 36cm x 27cm (Box 27)
    - [Unidentified]: Ralph Maradiaga, 1980[?]; #1/7, 38cm x 28.5cm (Box 27)
    - Hombre: Ralph Maradiaga, 1980; #3/5, 38cm x 56cm (Box 27)
    - [Unidentied]: [Unknown], n.d.; linoleum block print, 41cm x 55cm (Box 27)
      Positve and negative images, side by side; black on grey, three children, female holding an owl
    - ojo de los dioses: Irene Perez, March, 1974; #4/25, 57cm x 46cm (Box 27)
      Inscribed: "para mi india Estercita..."
    - La Yaqui: Irene Perez, May, 1974; #10/11, 57cm x 46cm (Box 27)
    - [Unidentified portrait]: Patricia Rodriguez, n.d; 61cm x 45cm (Box 27)
    - Calendar Series: enero, by Robert Werner Bonilla, 1975; #50/125, 58.5cm x 44.5cm (Box 28)
    - Calendar Series: marzo, by Graciela Carillo, 1975; #35/125, 58.5cm x 44.5cm (Box 28)
    - Calendar Series: abril, by Juan Fuentes, 1975; #77/125, 58.5cm x 44.5cm (Box 28)
    - Calendar Series: mayo, by Irene Perez, December, 1974; #115/125, 58.5cm x 44.5cm (Box 28)
      Subtitled: "Huicholes - Alumbrando el pensamiento del Hombre"
    - Calendar Series: junio, by Roger T.[?] Reyes, 1975[?]; #50/140, 58.5cm x 44.5cm (Box 28)
    - Calendar Series: July, by Unamontes[?], [1975]; #76/125, 58.5cm x 44.5cm (Box 28)
      Subtitled: "Chicano Bad"
    - Calendar Series: agosto, by [Unidentified-Ester Hernandez?], [1975]; #29/125, 58.5cm x 44.5cm (Box 28)
    - Calendar Series: septiembre, by Fagana[?], 1975; #34/125, 58.5cm x 44.5cm (Box 28)
      Subtitled: "Frida Kahlo"
    - Calendar Series: octubre, by Jose Romero, 1975; #41/133, 58.5cm x 44.5cm (Box 28)
      Subtitled: "Maya Reina y Rey"
    - Calendar Series: November, by Patricia Rodriguez, 1975; #1/125, 58.5cm x 44.5cm (Box 28)
      Subtitled: "mujer india"
    - Calendar Series: Diciembre, by Carlos Loarca, 1975; #82/134, 58.5cm x 44.5cm (Box 28)
      Subtitled: "Qui Balam"
    - A Brief History of Latin America, by Consuelo Mendez Castillo, 1978; sengrafia[?], 66cm x 51cm (Box 28)
      Inscribed: "para ester con[?]"
    - [Unidentified], by Graciela Carillo, ca. 1973; silkscreen, 66cm x 51cm (Box 28)
    - Irene, by Patricia Rodriguez, n.d.; silkscreen, 1/25, 62.5cm x 48cm (Box 28)
    - Poster: Si, Se Puede! - An Evening in Solidarity with Dolores Huerte, 1990[?]; 64cm x 44.5cm (Box 28)
    - Poster: Juchitan de las Mujeres - Graciela Iturbide/Elena Poniatowska, 1986[?]; 86cm x 55cm (Box 28)
      Photograph on poster entitled: "Cuatro pescaditos"
    - Poster: Atelier XII, 1988: Dolores Guerrero-Cruz, 40.5cm x 61.5cm (Box 29)
      Print on poster entitled: "Pero en mi cama"
    - Poster: You Are On Aboriginal Land, 1984; 61cm x 46cm (Box 29)
      Poster production in support of Mimi Aboriginal Arts and Crafts, Australia, design by Marie McMahon
    - Poster: Posada - Volksprenten uit Mexico van Jose Guadalupe Posada 1852-1913, 1980; 56cm x 38.5cm (Box 29)
      Tropenmuseum Amsterdam 26 september tm 18 november 1980
    - Poster: Homenaje A Frida Kahlo - Galeria de la Raza/Studio 24, November 2 - December 17, 1978, 1980; silkscreen, 58.5cm x 44.5cm (Box 29)
      [...?] Garcia, signed as artist.
    - Poster: Oakland's Portrait - A mural by Daniel Galvez with Juan Karlos and Keith Sklar, 1981; 61cm x 45.5cm (Box 29)
      15th St Walkway between Broadway and San Pablo, Oakland, CA
    - Poster: Uvas No - Sunday 23 April, 1995, 57cm x 44.5cm (Box 29)
      Poster contains photographs of Cesar Chavez, and street sign of Cesar Chavez Blvd., San Francisco, 3200 block.
    - Poster: Juchitan De Las Mujeres - Graciela Iturbide, Augut 8 - September 16, 1989, 61cm x 46cm (Box 29)
      Poster contains photograph entitled: "Nuestra Senora de las Iguanas/Our Lady of the Iguanas," credited to Graciela Iturbide.
    - Poster: Culture and Society in Dialogue: Issues in Chicana Scholarship, 1993; 61cm x 45.5cm (Box 29)
      Held May 14, 1993, UC Irvine. Poster contains print entitled: "Portrait of the Artist as the Virgen de Guadalupe," credited to Yolanda M. Lopez.
    - Nude: Jose Ramon, 1951; ink drawing, 30cm x 23.5cm (Box 30)
    - [Unidentified], n.d.; print, #2/7, 40.5cm x 30.5cm (Box 30)
      Text related to skeletal figure in work reads: "Tu solo tu has llenado de luto mi vida abriendo una herida en mi corazon y por quererte olvidar"
    - Elvira's Funeral: Paul [...?], n.d.; print, #1/45, 38cm x 56cm (Box 30)
    - Guerilla...Madre...: Consuelo Mendez Castillo (overlays by Rupert Garcia); Andinos: Consuelo Mendez Castillo; Madre: Consuelo Mendez Castillo, 1974-1976; 44.5cm x 58.5cm (Box 30)
      Reproductions of Castillo's work, originals are silkcreens
    - Jublee: Graciela [Carillo?], 1981; 60.5cm x 46cm (Box 30)
      Inscribed: "Para a Ester"
    - Borinqueno Lindo - John Santos: Arotija, mounted photograph,31cm x 24cm (Box 30)
    - Nina de Vietnam: Waldo Nilo, n.d.; mounted photograph,50.5cm x 40.5cm (Box 30)
    - Split Image - Tijuana/Los Angeles: Patsi[?] Valdez, 1987; #43/66, 66cm x 50.5cm (Box 31)
    - War of the Dog Soldier: Susana Santos, n.d.; #21/96, 56cm x 76.5cm (Box 31)
    - Cocina Jaiteca: [Unidentified], 1988; #55/60, 56cm x 76.5cm (Box 31)
    - Camino Fargo: Yreina D. Cervantes, 1985; screenprint, #23/88, 106.5cm x 72.5cm (Box 31)
      Inscribed: "Para Ester, con respeto y admiracion, siguimos[?] en nuestro camino, un abrazo fuerte. La Yreina 5/29/88"
    - Estrella of the Dawn: Yreina D. Cervantes and [unidentified], 1985; screenprint, #59/60, 106.5cm x 72.5cm (Box 31)
    - Some Kind of Buckaroo: Jean La Marr, 1990; screenprint, #32/58, 66cm x 97cm (Box 31)
    - Self Portrait: Barbara Carrassco, 1984; screenprint, artist's proof, #1/2 101.5cm x 71cm (Box 31)
    - I Heard the Song of My Grandmothers, by Jean La Marr, silk screen print, #34/67, 97cm x 127cm (Box 32)
  - Miscellaneous, 1.7
    - Calendario de la Raza, 1999: Images of the Mujer (Box 33)
      Produced by La Raza Studies Department, San Fancisco State University: Work by, and essay on Ester Hernandez appears for the month oh August.
    - Destiny Manifesting: September 9-November 23, 1998, color print, 43cm x 28cm (Box 33)
      Exhibition poster, Galeria de la Raza, SF; design attributed to Rener Moreno and Yu Hobara
    - Stanford University Present Flor Y Canto, featuring Astrid Hadad y Los Tarzanes, color print, 43cm x 28cm (Box 33)
      Exhibition poster, featuring artwork by Ester Hernandez
    - Arte del Otro Mexico: fuentes y siginificados, 1994; color print, 46.5cm x 31.5cm (Box 33)
      Exhibition poster, Museo Regional de Santo Domingo, 11 February - March 30, 1994; featuring artwork by Ester Hernandez
    - Dias de los Muertos: Ancient Roots and Evolving Traditions, 1998; color print, 46.5cm x 31.5cm (Box 33)
      Exhibition poster, Oakland Museum of California, October 17-November 29, 1998, featuring artwork by Terese Bravo
    - El Centro Chicano, MEChA, and the Stanford Concert Network present: Viva Cesar Chavez Commeroration Week, 1998; color print, 46.5cm x 31cm (Box 33)
      Exhibition poster, designed by Ester Hernandez, typeset by Yu Hobara
    - El Centro Chicano and MEChA present: Viva Cesar Chavez ! Commemorative Celebration, 1997; color print, 46.5cm x 31cm (Box 33)
      Exhibition poster, Stanford University, April12,1997; designed by Ester Hernandez, typeset by Renee Moreno
    - Creativity Explored of San Francisco Year 2000 Calendar, monoprint, spiral bound, 43cm x 28cm (Box 33)
      Calendar featuring artwork by adults with disabilities; designed and coordinated by Ester Hernandez.
    - Ester Hernandez, 1974; black and white photograph, 28.5cm x 38.5cm (Box 33)
      Attributed to H. Castillo.
    - Women Singing in the Snow: A Cultural Analysis of Chicana Literature, 1995; book jacket enclosed in plastic (Box 33)
      Tey Diana Rebolledo work (University of Arizona Press, Tucson, AZ), featuring Ester Hernandez's print: Lydia Mendoza circa 1930
    - The San Francisco Bay Guardian, 1989; proof, 45.5cm x 30.5cm (Box 33)
      Cover page, June 5, 1989; features photograph of Ester Hernandez, in recognition of winning Guardian Outstanding Local Discovery Award
    - Ester Hernandez, 4" x 6" photograph, mounted on posterboard (Box 33)
      From "Immigrant Woman's Dress" exhibit display
    - Immigrant Woman's Dress display placard, n.d.; paper on posterboard, 35.5cm x 21.5cm (Box 33)
      From "Immigrant Woman's Dress" exhibit display; explanatory text.
    - Ester Hernandez in studio, Oakland, CA, ca. 1979; photograph (Box 34)
      photographer unknown; print made ca. 1985
    - Ester Hernandez taken at Posada de Colores, ca. 1978; photograph (Box 34)
      photographer unknown
    - Ester Hernandez, ca. 1978; photograph (Box 34)
    - Unidentified group, taken at Posada de Colores, Oakland, CA, ca. 1978; photograph (Box 34)
    - Ester Hernandez, ca. 1974; photograph (Box 34)
      Photographer: Arotcja JiHonilro
    - Ester Hernandez, ca. 1973; photograph (Box 34)
    - Window Installation of Ester Hernadez's exhibit, Galeria de la Raza, ca. 1988; photograph (Box 34)
    - No on "O": Vivia Cesar Chavez poltical sign, n.d.; corrugated coated cardboard (Box 35)
      autographed and inscribed by Dolores Huerta
    - United Farmworkers of America banner; Keep Cesar Chavez St. Campaign button, n.d.; Logo on red cloth, campaign button pinned to cloth, 55cm x 38cm (Box 35)
    - Cesar Chavez poster, n.d.; posterboard, 60cm x 41cm (Box 35)
      Produced by Room 17, 4th grade class, Washington Elementary School, Montebello, CA
    - Cesar Chavez: Portrait of La Causa: Octavio Ocampo, n.d.; color reproduction on paper, 63.5cm x 45.5cm (Box 35)
    - La Raza Centro Legal: Celebrating 22 Years of Community Power, n.d.; color print on paper, 61cm x 40.5cm (Box 35)
      Features Hernandez's image: Lydia Mendoza, Ciudad Juarez, Mexico, 1937
    - Galeria de la Raza: Calendario 1975, color print on paper, 74/125, 59cm x 44.5cm (Box 35)
      Signed by Rafael Maradiaga
    - San Francisco [exhibition poster], 1992; color reproduction on paper, 59.5cm x 42cm (Box 35)
      Exhibition held at Treffpunkt Rotebuhlplatz, Stuttgart, Germany, Sept. 19 - Oct. 18, 1992; Hernandez's print La Ofrenda featured on poster (2 copies)
    - Tonantzin Guadalupe: exhibition folder, 1998; color print on posterboard, 69cm x 47.5cm (Box 35)
      Exhibition held at El Centro Morelense de Las Artes, El Instituto de Cultura de Morelos, Mexico; image of the Virgin attributed to Rene F{...?].
    - New Horizons: Economic Strength and Educational Excellence: poster, 1991; color reproduction on paper, 48.5cm x 61cm (Box 35)
      Produced by the Congressional Hispanic Caucus Institute, Inc., for the National Hispanic Heritage Month, 1991; Hernandez's Juntos al Futuro featured image.
    - Viva Dolores Huerta: 65th Birthday Celebration, 1995; color print on paper, 68.5cm x 50.5cm, 5/100 (Box 35)
      Poster produced for celebration held April 29, 1995 at the Delancey Street Foundation, SF. Image attributed to Rupert [?] Garcia; autographed and inscribed by Dolores Huerta.
    - Flour bag, used as prop for "California Special"[?], n.d. (Box 36)
- Personal Writings, Projects, Series 2; .5 linear ft.
  In Series 2, typed manuscripts and drafts of essays, course outlines, and addresses given by Hernandez are found, along with photographs, slides, and negatives of projects that Hernandez was involved with.
  - Cuando Llegaron Los Flying Saucers/When the Flying Saucers Landed (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - La Pisca/the Harvest (unpublished) (Box 37, Folder 2)